<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>software on Homepage Jan Baer</title>
    <link>https://www.janbaer.de/categories/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in software on Homepage Jan Baer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.janbaer.de/categories/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How can I protect my external USB stick with a password on MacOS Sierra</title>
      <link>https://www.janbaer.de/posts/2016-11-05_howto_protect_usbstick_with_password_on_macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.janbaer.de/posts/2016-11-05_howto_protect_usbstick_with_password_on_macos/</guid>
      <description>To protect your USB-stick with a password you have to format it first with the Disk Utility program to the Mac OS Extended (Journaled) format with the GUI-Partitiontable.
Attention Please make a backup before you&amp;rsquo;re formatting it!!!
Then just go into the terminal and enter diskutil list. Here should see the USB drive listed (in my case it&amp;rsquo;s /dev/disk2)
In case you&amp;rsquo;ve only one partition on this USB stick you&amp;rsquo;ve to convert disk2s2 to a AppleCoreStorage with using you own passphrase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to run a scheduled job within a Docker container</title>
      <link>https://www.janbaer.de/posts/2016-10-23_howto_run_a_sheduled_job_within_a_docker_container/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.janbaer.de/posts/2016-10-23_howto_run_a_sheduled_job_within_a_docker_container/</guid>
      <description>For some reasons it could be necessary to execute a job in scheduled time. When running the job within a Docker container there&amp;rsquo;re two ways to do this.
The first would be to create a cron job on the server on which Docker is running and let them execute the job with docker run.
The second way would be to let do everything within the Docker container. But you don&amp;rsquo;t need to implement any scheduling functionality since it&amp;rsquo;s out of the box available from any Linux based container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quicktip - Move windows between desktops on MacOSX</title>
      <link>https://www.janbaer.de/posts/2015-10-17_quicktip_movewindowsbetweetendesktopsonmacosx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.janbaer.de/posts/2015-10-17_quicktip_movewindowsbetweetendesktopsonmacosx/</guid>
      <description>To move windows, click and hold on any window titlebar and hit the shortcut you defined for the desktop (in my case it&amp;rsquo;s command+1,2,3) and the window will automatically moved to this dekstop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>